Remote working has been around for
some time but has become essential
for many businesses over the last
year or so due to the pandemic and
looks like continuing trend for many
companies for the foreseeable future.
This means that cyber security has
become of greater concern for businesses.
Rigorous and powerful cybersecurity
is needed to protect employees working
remotely such as VPN or investing
in the more secure zero trust model.
In a world where employees could be
working from many places such as at home,
a coffee shop, or on holiday; zero trust
works on the principle of don’t trust
by default and uses additional factors
to assess whether to grant access.
These could be where is
the user signing in from?
What time are they signing in?
Is this a normal time when they
usually sign in between 9am and 5pm?
What device are they accessing from?
And many other potential factors that
could indicate a risky sign-in attempt.
On site security is easier to handle
than using unsafe WiFi networks.
When using untrusted WiFi networks,
employees should be sure to use
a corporate VPN so that their
connection is encrypted end-to-end.
We must also be aware of human error along
with other vulnerabilities such as weak
password or the use of the same password.
Working should always take place in safe
environments, so as not to have security
impacted by having others present.
That's why it’s not ideal to work on a
train, in a cafe or in a hotel or business
reception or even in the park, where
others can see important information
and security cannot be guaranteed.
Whilst working in public, employees should
be wary of shoulder-surfing that people
can’t view any potentially sensitive
data that they may have on screen.
Privacy screens can be used which blur
the screen of anyone who is not sat
directly in front of the computer.